module.exports = {
  gameType: 'text',
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'the bubonic plague was spread by', 
      a: 'fleas', 
      b: 'mouse urine',
      c: 'mold spores',
      d: 'airborne (coughing and sneezing)',
      answer: 'a'
    },
    {
      question: 'the cause of death in ebola is typically', 
      a: 'sepsis', 
      b: 'severe low blood pressure',
      c: 'lungs filling with fluid',
      d: 'head falling off',
      answer: 'b'
    },
    {
      question: 'the japanese smallpox epidemic killed off how much of japan? ', 
      a: '10%', 
      b: '20%',
      c: '33%',
      d: '50%',
      answer: 'c'
    },
    {
      question: 'which island was the quarantine spot for the last US cholera outbreak?', 
      a: 'key west, fl', 
      b: 'orcas island, wa',
      c: 'alcatraz, ca',
      d: 'swinburne island, ny',
      answer: 'd'
    },
    {
      question: 'diseases that can be transferred between species are called', 
      a: 'zoonotic', 
      b: 'toxoplastic',
      c: 'genusplaidous',
      d: 'fergalicious',
      answer: 'a'
    },
    {
      question: 'the plague of justinian originated in', 
      a: 'central asia', 
      b: 'southern africa',
      c: 'northern europe',
      d: 'southeast asia',
      answer: 'a'
    },
    {
      question: 'yellow fever gets its name from', 
      a: 'being spread by bees', 
      b: 'causing jaundice',
      c: 'disproportionately affecting blondes',
      d: 'racism',
      answer: 'b'
    },
    {
      question: 'the smallpox vaccine was developed in', 
      a: '1871', 
      b: '1911',
      c: '1796',
      d: '1922',
      answer: 'c'
    },
    {
      question: 'which illness killed 20% of hawaii in the 1850s?', 
      a: 'the third plague', 
      b: 'cholera',
      c: 'whooping cough',
      d: 'measles',
      answer: 'd'
    },
    {
      question: 'spanish flu got its name from', 
      a: 'originating in spain', 
      b: 'censors blocking coverage from WW1 battle spots',
      c: 'spanish merchants transmitting it',
      d: 'being carried in charcuterie',
      answer: 'b'
    }
  ]
};